UX Related Skills

<u>Portfolio</u> My portfolio showcases interaction design and UX research: http://inhll.info

<u>Communication</u> I am a clear, concise writer and have experience collaborating with

interdisciplinary teams, both local and remote (international).

<u>CSS/HTML & Code</u> I am fluent in HTML, CSS and comfortable prototyping in Bootstrap. I have

completed Codecademy and Free Code Camp HTML/CSS/JS courses.

Applications I'm fluent in Adobe Creative Suite, MS Office, Google Docs, Basecamp, Axure

RP, Trello, Morae, Silverback, and many more. I am a quick learner.

Sketching & Drawing I sketch my ideas on paper to help solve problems creatively and clearly

explain my ideas and I have formal training in graphic facilitation methods.

Work Experience

User Experience Designer at ZS Associates, *Evanston*

Aug. 2015 - Present

My work at ZS Associates focused on improving the usability of enterprise pharmaceutical sales and compensation software. I led a major research project to improve the efficacy of users when configuring one of our flagship tools. For this project I planned, designed, and performed primary research and analysis with international users, performed wireframing and validation of the resulting designs, and presented findings to internal stakeholders. To bring this work to fruition I worked with multiple international agile development teams, attending backlog grooming, retros, demos, and helped create best practices to ensure effective UX support for development efforts.

Sr. Associate Interaction Designer at Manifest Digital, *Chicago*

Aug. 2014 - Aug. 2015

I solve meaningful problems by applying interaction design and user experience principles. My focus is on crafting award-winning enterprise insurance mobile experiences which help customers accomplish their goals quickly and efficiently. I do this by developing process flows to understand the ecosystem, detailed wireframe iterations, and by working closely with QC and development teams.

I provide course development and support on instructional tools for the nationally ranked College of Computing and Digital Media (CDM). My primary focus is planning for and facilitating the transition of 200+ CDM faculty from the home-grown learning management system to Desire2Learn with outreach, workshops, training, and documentation. In addition to providing primary support for CDM, I assist other ITCs on my team in supporting their faculty through my comprehensive system knowledge and Super Administrator role in D2L.

In this role, I provided course development support to Senior Instructional Technology
Consultants and departments in the College of Liberal Arts and Social Sciences. I also offered technical training and support for faculty by developing, maintaining, and delivering trainings and related materials. I led and supported the migration of documentation to a wiki, documented internal processes, responded to and submitted vendor tickets, and held a Supervisory Administrator role in D2L.

I provided internal and customer-facing application support within 24 hours in an environment of 24,000+ users, daily application administration of Blackboard versions 6, 7, and 8 including patching, Building Block installation, and daily system maintenance; I also assisted with Wimba, TurnItIn, Mailman, and Streaming Media administrative tasks. I led the migration of existing DePaul course materials from Blackboard to Desire2Learn.

Web Designer; Training & Support at SpringCM, Chicago Sept. 2006 - June 2007 My primary role involved the creation of marketing materials for the company website, development of visual web assets, web code-base, and deploying code to production, in addition to developing training, print materials, email newsletters and other collateral. I also maintained the UNIX web development environment.

Education

MS in Human-Computer Interaction	Studying HCI/UX taught me the importance of air-tight
DePaul University, Chicago	research when observing complex interactions to determine
June 2016	the best way to meet the goals of product users and stakeholders.
	stakerioiders.

BA in Geography, GIS concentration

DePaul University, Chicago

June 2004

Studying globalization and urbanization taught me the importance of observing complex systems and effectively communicating the big picture to incentivize action.

Professional Development

Completed The Grove's Principles of Graphic Facilitation
workshop and all supplementary materials (2016). Attended
UX Immersions (2016). Participated in World Information
Architecture Day Chicago events on behalf of Manifest
Digital (2015). Attended various UX Meetups and IXDA
Events in Chicago (ongoing).

ian.anders.hall@gmail.com | 312-607-1312 | @inhll 6339 N. Ridge Ave #3N, Chicago, IL 60660